## **Lalit Tanwar**

Address: Delhi, India | Mobile No.: +91-9930104050 | Email ID: <u>lalit.tanwar07@gmail.com</u>
Website: www.lalittanwar.com

## **Career Summary**

Experience designing Web and mobile applications framework for e-commerce and finance domains. An opensource contributor for some creatively designed UI frameworks.

3+ years of leading the User Interface (UI) development team – joined the Development team as a UI owner of the product at idea inception stage. Designed the UI architecture and implemented complex features in easy-to-use manner. It was fantastic learning experience working with the UI team at Dion Global Solutions Pvt. Ltd.

2.5+ years of designing UI architecture for the world's leading e-commerce product, designing complete UI architecture of travel ecosystem (Aertrip) and designing Online Logistics Platform (OLP) for Snapdeal.

# **Skills Summary**

Web Architecture | Leadership | Algorithms | Analytics | Data Science | Problem Solving

# **Experience Summary**

Unicommerce Pvt. Ltd. Delhi, IN

#### **User Interface Architect**

**NOVEMBER 2014 – TILL DATE** 

Uniware is a world-class product that is integrated with world's leading marketplace and cart solution providers such as Magento, Shopify, Amazon, eBay, Flipkart and Snapdeal. Uniware is designed for multi-channel retail platforms with live inventory updates.

<u>Technologies</u> - Object Oriented JavaScript, GruntJS, NPM Bower, RivetsJS, Compass/Sass, UnderscroreJS

#### Roles and Responsibilities

- Migrated all the modules written in traditional JSP to latest UI based technologies with modular approach.
- Implemented complete rendering of HTML on UI using client-side templating.
- Used pub-sub architecture to make each component a module to communicate with other modules in an asynchronous-way
- Implemented x-tags and plug-in as per on-going business requirements.
- Provided direction to UI team on writing functionality based on the designed architecture.
- Worked as a team and obtained the work output as expected by the product team.

Unidesk is a customer support tool with features such as real-time chat, ticket management and easy-to-integrate web client.

<u>Technologies</u> – Object Oriented JavaScript, GruntJS, NPM Bower, RivetsJS, Compass/Sass, UnderscroreJS, HTML2Canvas

#### Roles and Responsibilities

- Designed architecture of entire tool with easy-to-use features
- · Contributed in design and discussion with back-end team for smooth implementation across all departments.
- Integrated the tool with multiple internal products with ease.

Online Logistics Platform is a delivery tracking tool used by Snapdeal. It is built for supply chain and logistics to ensure faster delivery of Snapdeal products to their customers.

<u>Technologies</u> - Object Oriented JavaScript, GruntJS, NPM Bower, RivetsJS, Compass/Sass, UnderscroreJS, GoogleMap, MQTT

#### Roles and Responsibilities

- Designed client (Web and mobile) architecture of entire tool with easy-to-use features
- Worked on performance of the system that gives awesome user experience.
- Worked as a team to deliver the product as per prescribed timelines by the product team
- Designed and architected other small products at Snapdeal, such as ControlTower, TaxEngine,
- Ensured timelines are met working with different teams on different products.

Team Lead – dfferentia

Senior Web Consultant - dfferentia

Consultant – dfferentia

APRIL 2014 – NOVEMBER 2014

APRIL 2012 – MARCH 2014

JULY 2011 – MARCH 2012

dfferentia is a pricing engine and trading platform for FX Options OTC derivatives instruments. It is built for front office analytics used by traders and hedge funds organizations.

Technologies - Java, Servlet 3.0, JSP, JavaScript, jQuery, redis, iFrames, XDM, Longpolling

### Roles and Responsibilities

- Designed the UI architecture for dfferentia taking care of the workflow of different components such as market data module, pricing libraries, authentication modules.
- Implemented Single Sign On (SSO) authentication to integrate dfferentia with external clients.
- Created custom widgets, plug-ins and HTML grid with multiple data type handling based on the complex business requirements
- Worked on HA compliance to avoid user interruption in case of the server failure
- Designed and implemented the white labelling infrastructure for the organizations to easily customize dfferentia and use as their own easy-to-use interface.
- Designed and implemented Server-Browser-Communication infrastructure (2-way-async-communication) to ensure real-time notifications across the system.
- Built a chat tool to offer real-time interaction using the "Long Polling" technique

# **Education Summary**

- Master of Technology in Computer Science from Indian Institute of Technology IIT Mumbai, 2009 2011
- Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science from Thapar Institute of Engineering and Technology 2005-2009

## **Design & Architecture Projects**

- rudrax/boot An opensource PHP framework for server side based on MVC. The scope of framework is to provide flexibility to the developers to use the framework and define data and behavior according to their choice. It integrates Smarty, readbeans, Annotations Support, phpfastcache.
  - URL https://github.com/rudraks/boot
- grunt-bootloader Development framework for UI development, from development to deployment.
  - URL <a href="https://www.npmjs.com/package/grunt-bootloader">https://www.npmjs.com/package/grunt-bootloader</a>
- Bootloader A replacement for requireJs, for transitive dependency management on client side, for both local and third party libraries. Based on headJs.
  - URL https://github.com/webmodule/bootloader

### **Technical Skills**

- Programming Languages C, C++, Java
- Web HTML, PHP, JSP, JavaScript, NodeJS, Smarty, Google Map
- Web Performance Techniques: Long Polling, WebSockets, STOMP, Pub-Sub Architect, WebRTC
- UI Libraries & Frameworks ¡Query, ¡Query-UI, UnderscoreJS, Bootstrap, SockJS, RivetsJS
- Java Libraries & Frameworks Spring, Jackson, Spring-Boot
- Scripting Languages Python, ShellScript
- Databases MySQL, Oracle, PhpMyAdmin, redbeans
- Operating System Linux, Windows
- IDE NetBeans, SpringSource/Eclipse, WebStorm, Idea
- Version Control System GIT
- Build Tool & Package Manager gradle, GruntJS, Bower, Composer, Compass/Sass, NPM

### **External Links**

- LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/lalittanwar
- Stackoverflow http://careers.stackoverflow.com/ltanwar
- GitHub https://github.com/Int
- NPM https://www.npmjs.com/~Int